Eugene Rakhimov

Address: 23 Hankey street, Wellington | Tel: 022 170 4992 | Email: gin3002@gmail.com | NZ Resident |

Github: https://github.com/EugenRakhimov | Linked In: https://nz.linkedin.com/in/eugenirakhimov

SUMMARY

I am recently graduated from Enspiral Dev Academy, a highly intensive software development bootcamp in Wellington with an agile environment. This followed 8 years' experience as a developer and IT security professional. I have been recognized for initiative, problem solving skills and creativity in both business process modelling and programming. Proven track record of success as IT specialist across a variety of industries and sectors. I am looking for software developer position.

KEY COMPETENCIES AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Software development in agile environment
- Object-oriented programming in Ruby, JavaScript, C++, VBA, C#
- Well-versed in web-development frameworks: Ruby-on-Rails, ASP.NET, AngularJS
- Databases and SQL programming(T-SQL)
- Client-focused, bi-lingual communicator with strong internal and external relationship building skills
- Hard working, team player, willing to share knowledge and collaborate to achieve team objectives
- User needs analysis, user stories, user testing
- Documentation of business requirements, business process modeling and analysis, and subsequent system design and development to meet user requirements
- Application of Rational Rose, UML, IDEF and tools and languages to systems modeling and implementation
- Familiar with virtualisation technologies
- Comprehensive knowledge of Information security, control programs, business processes, tools, security, risk and policies

CAREER HISTORY

Enspiral Dev Academy (Wellington)

Software developer (student)

June 2015 - September 2015

Accountabilities and Achievements

- Software development in agile environment, including:
- E-commerce application prototype (<u>battle ships store</u>) based on Sinatra network (personal project)
- · API-consuming applications, based on Javascript, JQuery and Sinatra(personal project)
- Team project <u>Tetris game application</u>, developed main game logic and integration interface part, mostly model and controller part in MVC, on Javascript.
- Group project <u>Social network/middle man service</u> for connecting tradesmen and clients, wrote controllers and views on Ruby-on-Rails, working on AngularJS view.
- Successfully finished all projects, helped other team members during weekly sprints on final project, facilitate TDD among team members and actively used red-green-refactoring approach myself, using Capybara, RSPEC.
- · Extensively used Git, and was a git master for team projecs, resolved merge conflicts.

J&T Bank (Moscow)

(Part of the J&T Group, J&T Bank is an international financial institution, with total assets of 4 billion rubles and €729 million equity.)

SQL developer

February 2013 - February 2015

Accountabilities and Achievements

- Was promoted from previous role in the same organisation.
- Was named among most efficient and valuable IT department employees in 2014.
- · Responsible for gathering system requirements through interviews with key stakeholders
- Designed software solutions to improve organizational efficiency and productivity
- Designed new SQL reports which met requirements
- · Developed internal procedures and triggers for MS SQL server based core banking system.
- Deployed new remote banking system for private clients, and developed integration module with core banking system.
- Assisted in testing the new system and making sure it meets the users' needs
- Core banking system application support successfully solved user problems in high pressure environment
- Deployment of core banking system changes and new modules
- Remote banking system client support helped to solve client problems, was known for proactive involvement, client focus and ability to solve most complicated issues. Worked with most demanding and valuable clients.
- Continued supervision of security management processes and provided help and advice to new information security managers

Information Security Manager

August 2011 - February 2013

Accountabilities and Achievements

- Responsible for planning, leading, implementing and controlling the bank's internal security compliance function
- Developed IT security documentation, through successfully aligning business needs with information security procedures, standards and policies
- Implement the Bank's Data Loss Prevention (DLP) system for removable media to assist in preventing data leaks by employees
- Implement the Bank's One Time Password (OTP) system for remote banking to reduce threat rate to clients
- Conducted analysis of business processes within the bank
- Remote banking system client support

REIGNVOX (Moscow)

(Established in 2008 by Bell Integrator, Reignvox specialises in the provision of services in the fields of information security and compliance)

IT Security Analyst

September 2009 – August 2011

Accountabilities and achievements

Eugene Rakhimov

- Manage information systems compliance audits from pre-audit planning to final reporting
 - Obtain information to establish audit plan
 - o Gather evidence through review of third-party contracts and service level agreements, review of information systems policies and procedures, standard and documentation
 - o Evaluate business processes of auditee
 - o Recommend mitigation measures
 - o Prepare Audit Report
- Successfully undertook IT compliance audit projects in local branches of large multinational companies including Societe Generale and Tele2, and local companies including Russlavbank; often completing audits ahead of schedule.
- · With business analytics division gathered functional requirements for new compliance-oriented software

Advanced Solutions (Moscow)

Cryptography analyst

May 2007 - May 2009

Accountabilities and achievements

- Documented division and enterprise-wide business processes, through systems and requirement identification and analysis
- Developed a Business Enterprise Architecture framework, identifying and documenting Advanced Solutions' core and supporting business processes
- Modelled business process using Unified Modelling Language (UML) and Integrated Definition (IDEF) methodology
- Instrumental in supporting the organisational goal of retaining cost-effective production while achieving increased quality and efficiency, as well as heightened customer satisfaction.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

PhD (Information Security), Ufa State Aviation Technical University, 2006

Master of Information Security, Ufa State Aviation Technical University, 2003

REFEREES

Referee details will be provided upon request